Alright, here's an exercise for you.
Tudo bem, aqui est um exerccio para voc.
So, in the Mocking folder, look at EmployeeController.
Ento, na pasta Mocking, olhe para EmployeeController.
This is an example of code that you
Este  um exemplo de cdigo que voc v em
see in a lot of ASP.NET MVC applications. Now this is
um monte de ASP. Aplicaes NET MVC. Agora este no
not a fully working example, it's purely simulation, because here we don't have
um exemplo totalmente funcional,  puramente simulao, porque aqui
an ASP.NET MVC project. We have a simple class library.
no temos um ASP. Projeto NET MVC. Ns temos uma biblioteca de classes simples.
But that aside, let's see what's happening here. So
Mas isso de lado, vamos ver o que est acontecendo aqui. Ento, nessa
in this class, we have this private field of type
classe, temos esse campo particular
EmployeeContext. This is part of entity framework.
do tipo EmployeeContext. Isso faz parte do framework da entidade.
So if you look down here, this EmployeeContext
Ento, se voc olhar para baixo, este EmployeeContext se parece
looks like a db context in entity framework, so it has
com um contexto de banco de dados no framework de
a property of type, DbSet of Employee.
entidade, ento ele tem uma propriedade do tipo, DbSet of Employee.
Here we should actually derive this from DB context, I forgot to do that, but
Aqui ns deveramos realmente derivar isso do contexto DB, eu esqueci de fazer isso, mas isso realmente
it doesn't really matter, because we don't want to run this code. So,
no importa, porque ns no queremos rodar este cdigo. Ento, temos
we have this EmployeeContext and we have initialized
este EmployeeContext e inicializamos
this in the constructor. We have this method, delete
isso no construtor. Temos esse mtodo, delete
Employee, takes an integer, that's the ID of the employee,
Employee, leva um inteiro, esse  o ID do
now here over these three lines, we try to delete this
funcionrio, agora aqui nessas trs linhas, tentamos deletar esse
employee from the database. So first, we try
funcionrio do banco de dados. Ento, primeiro, tentamos encontrar
to find that employee, then remove it from the context
esse funcionrio, remov-lo do contexto e, nesse
and at this point, that employee is marked for deletion.
ponto, esse funcionrio  marcado para excluso.
But changes are not persisted to the database, yet.
Mas as alteraes no so persistidas no banco de dados, ainda.
When we call DB.save changes,
Quando chamamos DB. salvar alteraes, a estrutura de entidade
entity framework generates the right query, and sends it to the database.
gera a consulta correta e a envia ao banco de dados.
And at this point, the employee record (?) gets deleted.
E neste momento, o registro do empregado (? )  deletado.
And finally, we direct the user to the list of employees.
E finalmente, direcionamos o usurio para a lista de funcionrios.
So, if you want to unit test this method, you need to write,
Ento, se voc quiser testar esse mtodo, voc precisa
two tests, one is to ensure that this method
escrever, dois testes, um  garantir que esse mtodo
returns the right result. And this is what we call state
retorne o resultado correto. E isso  o que chamamos
based testing. Another test is to ensure
de testes baseados em estado. Outro teste  garantir
that this method deletes the given employee from the
que esse mtodo exclua o empregado determinado do
database. So first of all, you need to extract these few lines into a
banco de dados. Ento, primeiro de tudo, voc precisa
separate class, because these lines touch an external resource in this
extrair essas poucas linhas em uma classe separada, porque essas linhas tocam em
case, a database, so you want to extract this into a separate class
um recurso externo, neste caso, um banco de dados, ento voc quer extrair
like EmployeeStorage. Then, extract the interface,
isso em uma classe separada como EmployeeStorage. Em seguida, extraia a
injected in the constructor here, and finally,
interface, injetada no construtor aqui e, finalmente, declare
Assert that this method calls the right method
que esse mtodo chama o mtodo correto nesse
in that storage object. So, go ahead and
objeto de armazenamento. Ento, v em frente e
do this exercise, in the next lecture, we'll look at my solution.
faa este exerccio, na prxima aula, veremos a minha soluo.